Just a little while longer, my lady.
奥方様、もう少しにござりまするぞ
My lady, be strong.
Your child will be here any minute now.
奥方様、お気を確かに…もう少しにござりまする
"HALL OF HELL"
Sir Daigo?
醍醐様か…
One who steps into this Hall of Hell
has made a choice.
この地獄堂へ入られたということは、
To cast off Buddha and the gods
in favor of the demons.
神仏を捨てこの鬼神たちに…
I see it is futile to try and stop you.
もはやお止めすることはできますまいな…
But hear me one last time.
もう一度だけ言うておきましょう…
Sir Daigo.
醍醐様…
御仏の道を外れるは外道…
To cast off Buddha is to tread
the path of evil.
外道にあるは人にあらず…
It is to no longer be human.
If you cross this line,
hell will surely await you.
踏み出せば、この先あなた様を待っているのはただ地獄…
Priest, we are already living in hell.
上人殿…地獄とはこの世のことよ…
そなたらが日がな一日拝んでいた御仏の道など、どこにもありはせぬ…
The holy path to Buddha you pray for
exists nowhere.
You will pay the consequences.
では…どうあっても…
知れたこと…
I care not.
ありがたき…
I thank you, Sir.
これで救われまする…
This will be my salvation.
This world is indeed hell,
just as you said.
今の世は地獄…
日々祈りは空しゅう…
The prayers I offered
seemed more and more pointless.
いずれ我がうちに御仏への疑いが生まれるやもと…
I always feared that some day
I would begin to doubt Buddha.
その前に死ぬるは何より…
I am glad to die before that day comes.
Sir Daigo, please stay away
from the demons.
醍醐様…鬼神に近づいてはなりませぬ…
Do not let yourself succumb to evil.
生きながら外道に堕ちては…
It's too late for that.
もう…堕ちておる
12の鬼神に言う！我が名は醍醐景光
12 Demons, I am Daigo Kagemitsu.
Lord of Ishikawa,
加賀国守護者、
富樫政親様の配下にしてこの石川領領主である
and vassal to the governor of Kaga Province.
Repeated famines and epidemics
have swept my land,
度重なる飢饉と流行り病によって、我が領土の民、
死を待つばかりに痩せ衰えた…
enfeebling my people to the point of death.
このままでは生涯の望み…我が名を天下に轟かせることなど、
As things stand, I shall never attain
the power and renown I crave.
My ambitions will remain a mere dream.
夢のまた夢なり…
But I refuse to rely on the mercy of
Buddha or the gods.
だが！神仏にすがろうとは思わぬ。
これから申すこと、そなたらへの祈りではない。
What I am about to say to you
is not a prayer.
取引である！
I came to make a deal.
もし我が領土を守護し、我に天下を握らせるならば…
If you'll protect my land
and let me rule the country,
それより他に、我が手に入るものをやろう
I will give you anything of mine.
Anything. Take whatever you wish.
よいか、何でもだ！そなたたちの好きなものを取るがいい！
返答やいかに！
Do you hear me!
奥方様…もう少し…もう少しにて…
My lady, just a bit more.
南無観世音菩薩…ご加護を…
Goddess of Mercy, please protect me...
He is born!
おほほ、生まれましたぞ！おほほほほ…
What is it?
如何した！
My lord.
殿…
Is the baby born?
生まれたのか！
それが…
-何だ！ハッキリいたせ！
-Yes, but...
-What? Say it.
殿…生まれました…
He is born, my lord.
男の子にございまする
He is your son.
御方様…
-世継ぎか、でかしたぞ奥！
-My lady...
-An heir, you've done well!
殿、お待ちを！
Sir, no...!
I do not know what happened.
何事が起こったのか…
死んではおりませんが、手足どころか目も鼻も
He is alive, but has no limbs,
eyes, nor a nose.
皮膚もなくなってしまいました…
He doesn't even have any skin.
I will give you anything of mine.
手に入るものをやろう。
Anything. Take whatever you wish.
何でもだ！そなたたちの好きなものを取るがいい！
殿、わたくしは儚く愛おしいと思いました…
My lord, I feel a deep love
for this woeful child of ours.
どのような姿であろうとも、間違いなく殿とわたくしの子にございます
No matter his appearance, he is our son.
My dream will be fulfilled.
叶ったぞ…これで我が望みは叶った！
殿！
-鬼神が取引に応じたのだ…
-My lord?
-The demons agreed to the deal.
案ずることはない！
You need not worry.
よくぞ生んでくれた…
Thank you for bearing him.
どうするのです！その子をどこへ！
What are you doing, stop!
-Wait!
-Forget him. He never even existed.
待って！
-忘れよ…あれは初めからいなかったのだ
No! Don't!
いいえ！いいえ…！
奥方様！まだ起き上がってはなりませぬ！
My lady, you mustn't get up yet.
殿、お慈悲を！あの子を…！
Please, have mercy.
奥…！あれではどうせ長くは生きられぬ…
He wouldn't survive anyway.
ならば尚の事…我が胸で…
Then let him pass away in my arms.
Enough!
いい加減にいたせ！
赤子はまた生まれよう、いや生んでもらわなくてはならん…
You will bear another child. You must.
天下の世継ぎとなろうからな…
The next one will be
the heir of a great ruler.
What...
先程、雷が落ちたときに弾け飛んで…？
It was blown away
when the lightning struck.
産婆は、何かの身代わりではないかと…
The midwife said it sacrificed itself.
身代わり？
Sacrifice?
"HALL OF HELL"
Party is over
But I still wanna dance
I can't even sleep
Someday, one day my passion's fire will
From the beginning I knew
One day the flames would die out
Hey, I thought I didn't need anything
But even now, I'm so serious
Ah... I still have time to make it
Ah... but I’m gonna burn it up, baby
Sorry darling, it’s not that easy
But surely it’s not that bad either
Give me fire
Light it up, baby. I’m gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
Give me fire
Light it up, baby. I’m gonna burn it up, yeah
#1 The story of Daigo
何の因果か知らぬが…
Whatever could've caused this?
これでは、生きてるほうが地獄だろうて…
Either way, being alive
would only be harder for you.
Now, go on dear.
Buddha will take care of you.
さぁ…あの世で仏様に拾っておもらい…
何だろうかね…こんなことは慣れっこのはずだが…
I should be used
to this sort of thing by now.
お前…生きたいのか？
Do you desire to live?
あとは…お前さんの運次第だ…
The rest is up to your luck, dear boy.
臭うねぇ…
I smell something.
こりゃあ…悪さの臭いだ…
The stench of evil.
あれは…
What's there?
人ともつかぬ…
Not human.
いや、あやかしでもない…
Yet, not a ghoul, either.
何やら因果な臭いだねぇ…
I smell a curse.
加賀国ざかいにある醍醐景光の領地は、
Daigo Kagemitsu's land
at the border of Kaga.
度重なる飢饉を乗り越え、繁栄の一歩を辿り始めたこの日…
After overcoming many famines,
it was on its way to prosperity.
泣き声さえ上げられぬ小さな命の塊が、
But the tiny soul,
too weak to even let out a cry,
人知れず消えていったことを
quietly vanished off into obscurity.
領民の誰1人知る者はなかった
There was none in the land
who knew about it.
16 YEARS LATER
この頃、戦は常にどこかで起こり、
At that time, there was always a war
being fought somewhere.
人の命は石ころのように転がっていた
Human lives were hardly worth
more than a stone on the ground.
おぉ…もし、お前さま。
You there.
お前さまが、近頃仏に失った手足をつけて弔っているというお医者か…
Are you the doctor who gives prosthetics
to the dead to mourn for them?
寿海とか申される
Your name is Jukai, am I correct?
まことに、ご奇特な…
How worthy of you.
いや…ただの試作したものを捨てるよりはと思っただけのこと
I just figured it'd be better
than throwing away the prototypes.
それでも、仏は喜びましょう…
But I'm sure they are grateful for it.
さぁ、とっくり見てってくれ！どれもこれも都の極上品だよ！
Come, come, take a look.
Quality goods, straight from the capital.
ほら！この着物は貴族のお姫様が着ていた本物の絹。
This is real silk.
A wealthy princess wore it.
お姉さん、触ってみなって！
Come miss, feel it.
おっと、この壺はなんとあのヤマタノオロチの酒ガメだ…
And this is a sake jug from
the Yamata no Orochi legend.
他じゃ手に入らない掘り出し物ばかり！
All one-of-a-kind quality items.
安くしとくよ！買ってくれたら、この干し魚もおまけにつけちゃう！
I'll give you a bargain.
I'll even throw in these dried fish.
さぁ、早いもん勝ちだ！
First come, first served.
げ…
Yikes.
見つけたぜどろろ…
Found you, Dororo.
こいつは俺たちが運んでいたもんだなぁ…
This is the load we were carrying,
isn't it?
どこにそんな証拠があんだよ
Got any proof?
やかましい！腹減って死にそうだってぇから、
荷物番に雇ってやりゃあコレだ…
Shut up! You said you were starving,
so we hired you to look after our goods.
聞けば、あちこちで似たようなことやらかしてるそうじゃねぇか…
This is your usual trick, we hear.
大したタマだぜ
You little rascal.
見つけたらこらしめてくれって頼まれちまった
Some guys asked me to make sure
you paid for it.
ハッ…このご時世、子供だからって油断するほうがマヌケなんだよ。
It's your fault for being so naive.
勉強になったろ？
You should learn from me.
あぁ。だからもう手加減はしねぇ。
Right, no more nice guy.
大人と同じ仕置きを受けてもらうぜ！
You'll pay for this, just like an adult.
待てこのガキ！
Stop, you little brat! Oops.
お前らみたいなウスノロに捕まるかよ！
Catch me if you can.
待ちやがれ！このクソガキ！
-Get back here, dammit!
-We'll get you!
すいませんねぇ！
Thank you, mister.
ほら、ボーっとしてないでちゃんとお礼言いな！
Don't just stand there, say thank you.
母ちゃん、今日お祭り？
Is there a festival today, Mama?
何言ってんの、こないだ終わったばっかだろ？
Of course not.
We just had one not long ago.
だって…あの兄ちゃんお面つけてた
But he had a mask on.
クソッ…どこ行きやがった
Where'd he go, dammit.
何だ…？
What's this?
Oh, crap.
わっ！臭ぇ！
馬フンだ！
Horse manure!
Wash your faces with those,
and come back later.
そいつでツラ洗って出直してきな！
He's asking for it now.
えぇいもう勘弁ならねぇ…！
Ah, that was fun.
はぁ…面白かった。
Too bad about that load though.
That was good stuff.
けどあの荷物は残念だったな、上物だったのに…
Oh well. I'll just go for the next fool.
ま、また次のマヌケを狙うか
What is it? Can't find your mommy?
何だ？お前。おっかちゃんとはぐれたのか？
You hungry? Oh, all right.
腹減ってんのか？しょうがねぇな…
No, I can't. You have to learn
how to live on your own now.
いや、ダメだ。お前はこれから1人で生きてかなきゃなんねぇんだ。
It wouldn't do you any good.
甘やかしちゃ、お前のためになんねぇ
Learn how to find your own food.
人に頼らず自分で取ってくるんだ。
I'm saying this for your own good.
ダメダメ、お前のために言ってるんだからな
You're mine now, Dororo.
もう逃さねぇぜどろろ…
Hey, let go of him!
オイ！そいつ離せ！離せよ！
Is he yours?
Then he'll pay for what you did.
こいつお前のか？だったらお前の代わりに痛い目見てもらおうか…
-Stop it.
-Then do what we say.
やめろ！
じゃあ大人しくしな…
Had enough? Don't you ever steal again.
これで懲りたろう！二度と悪さすんじゃねぇぞ！
-You brat!
-You asked for it.
このガキ！
-まだ足んねぇのか！
Enough.
もういい…
Never show your face here again, got it?
さっさとこの町から出て行けよ…いいな
No.
い…嫌だ…
Nobody orders me around.
おいらは誰の指図も受けねぇ…
I choose where I live!
どこにいようとおいらの勝手だ！
You wanna die, huh?
そんなに死にてぇか…
Be my guest!
望み通りにしてやる！
Bring me that straw mat.
I'm wrapping him up.
オイ！そこのムシロ持ってこい！簀巻きにしてやる
Okay, Boss.
はいよ
What are you doing? Hurry up.
オイ！何やってんだ、早くしろ！
Boss, there's some weird guy up there.
親方…なんか気味悪ぃヤツが…
Huh?
何だ…？
He's got a face like a doll.
あの顔…人形みてぇだ
His eyes too. Where's he looking?
目ン玉もだよ…どこ見てんだか
Creep.
確かに気味悪ぃ
Hey you, got a problem?
オイ兄ちゃん！なんか文句あんのか！
We're not some bullies, you know.
We're the ones being bullied.
俺たちがガキいじめてると思ったら大間違いだぜ！
いじめられたのはこっちだ
Hey, you hear me?
オイ！聞こえてんのか？
What, you wanna fight?
なっ…やんのか兄ちゃん？
No, I don't think he's looking at us.
違う…あいつが見てんの、多分俺たちじゃねぇよ…
Those eyes.
あの目…
He's looking behind us.
俺たち通り越して、後ろ…
Huh? There's nothing out there.
何だよ、後ろなんか誰もいねぇよ…
Just some floating garbage.
何でぇ、ゴミが流れてきただけじゃねぇか…
What the...
It ate him...?
食われ…ちまった？
He's not looking at it!
あの兄ちゃん、化け物見てねぇ！
Wow, that was amazing!
ハハッ…すげぇ、すげぇよ兄ちゃん！
Your face. Those eyes,
ears and all are fake, right?
なぁ…あんたのその顔、目も耳も作りもんだよな？
How can you see?
なんで周りが分かんだ？
But you can't hear, can ya?
でも…その耳じゃ聞こえないんだろうけどさ
I wouldn't be able to walk a step
with my eyes closed.
ダメだ…おいら目を閉じたら怖くて1歩も歩けねぇ。
But you run and jump
without using a cane.
なのに兄ちゃんは杖もなしに走ったり飛んだり！
How do you do that?
一体どうなってんだよ…
What is it? What's wrong?
え…？なんで…どうしたんだよ？
Are you hurt?
怪我したのか？
What's going on? Your skin...
な…何だよ、これ！顔の皮が…
"HALL OF HELL"
What the...
これは…！
T-This can't be!
ま…まさか…！
Mother!
母上ー！
I hunted a turtledove for you.
It will make you strong.
山鳩を仕留めて参りました！精がつきますぞ！
I, Tahomaru, will cook it for you.
この多宝丸が調理いたしまする！
How wonderful.
それは楽しみな…
It rained like this that day, too.
あの日も、こんな雨だった…
My dear son.
坊や…
Hyakkimaru.
百鬼丸…
You... Your face...
顔…顔が…！
What's going on?
なんだ…？どうなってんだよ…！
What are you?
あんた…何なんだ…？
Are you human?
人間なのかよ！？
"Deiki"